<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Manav&#39;s Web-log</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Manav&#39;s Web-log</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cloudflare is bad</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cloudflare-is-bad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cloudflare-is-bad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m going to keep this brief: never use Cloudflare for domain registration or hosting if you can help it. Here are three reasons:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you register a domain with Cloudflare, you cannot use nameservers anywhere else. I cannot think of a single other modern registrar with such aggressive vendor-lock in. The most salient problem with this is that if you want to take advantage of a CDN, you are stuck with Cloudflare, which leads me to the second problem:&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cloudflare’s CDN has abysmal UX. Due to some sort of abstruse caching policy, it does not seem to update changes to CSS files on the edge. The deployment pipeline appears to be inhabited by sentient and capricious machine-elves who will only allow particular parts of your website to be exposed to the wider world. Perhaps their whims adhere to some sort of aesthetic logic beyond my comprehension, and this inability to execute a basic hosting feature is actually an act of protest against my design choices.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, I have seen too many scary &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/CloudFlare/comments/154xmd2/be_careful_about_cloudflare_for_important_tasks/&#34;&gt;stories&lt;/a&gt; about Cloudflare’s automated systems locking people out of their accounts due to IP changes and other unpredictable actions. The common pattern is that after the lock-out, they are stuck in hellish catch-22s in which they have to be logged into the account that they are locked out of in order to access support. The general response amongst ardent Cloudflare defenders (get a life, by the way!) is that you ought to have multiple accounts for any load-bearing domains. I do not know whether I live in some kind of bizarro-world, but this is insane to me. I have jumped ship before I too end up becoming another protagonist of a Heller novel.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ve had better luck with &lt;a href=&#34;https://namecheap.com/&#34;&gt;Namecheap&lt;/a&gt;, and a particularly skillful &lt;a href=&#34;https://joodaloop.com&#34;&gt;webdev&lt;/a&gt; has told me good things about &lt;a href=&#34;https://porkbun.com/&#34;&gt;Porkbun&lt;/a&gt;. You deserve better than Cloudflare.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some poems I like</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/poems/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/poems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I came across &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/03/06/put-my-house&#34;&gt;this poem&lt;/a&gt; in the New Yorker and it made me despair somewhat. This is my retaliation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-shropshire-lad-xl&#34;&gt;A Shropshire Lad, XL&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A.E. Housman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&#xA;Into my heart an air that kills&#xA;From yon far country blows:&#xA;What are those blue remembered hills,&#xA;What spires, what farms are those?&#xA;&#xA;That is the land of lost content,&#xA;I see it shining plain,&#xA;The happy highways where I went&#xA;And cannot come again.&#xA;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;moonlight-night&#34;&gt;Moonlight Night&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;R.M. Rilke&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wellness as work ethic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/wellness-work-ethic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/wellness-work-ethic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This essay was originally published in Vol VI Issue 2 of the&lt;/em&gt; RUMS Review &lt;em&gt;magazine. You can read the full issue &lt;a href=&#34;https://online.fliphtml5.com/plvos/ywhu/#p=35&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Modern medicine has put health back into the hands of the individual. A slew of evidence over the past few decades has established exercise, mindful eating, and other such lifestyle interventions as necessities for the maintenance of good health. This evidence base has spawned public messaging campaigns, legislation such as the Soft Drinks Industry Levy and the proposed phased ban on cigarettes, and (perhaps most conspicuously) a 5-billion-dollar behemoth of a wellness industry. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The serotonin theory of depression: a post-mortem analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/serotonin-theory-post-mortem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/serotonin-theory-post-mortem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This piece was written in collaboration with &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/Aryan_AroraA&#34;&gt;Aryan Arora&lt;/a&gt; and originally published in Vol XI Issue 1 of the&lt;/em&gt; RUMS Review &lt;em&gt;Magazine. The full issue is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://online.fliphtml5.com/plvos/ujxj/index.html#p=1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Major depressive disorder, commonly referred to as depression, lies in the unfortunate realm of conditions which are simultaneously widespread, debilitating, stigmatised, and poorly understood. It is one of psychiatry’s paradigm-defining maladies; being the most common mental illness, it affects more than 264 million people globally and is the second leading cause of chronic disability worldwide. Its enigmatic nature has occupied minds both medical and artistic for millennia, from Hippocrates’ “humoral melancholia” to the “anomie” of the Romantics. Contemporary understandings emphasise a triad of symptoms: low mood, anhedonia (inability to feel pleasure in normally pleasurable activities), and fatigue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Psychiatrist, heal thyself</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/psychiatrist-heal-thyself/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/psychiatrist-heal-thyself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I was left with some reflections (and doubts) after the psychiatry lectures I received over my first year in medical school. I have been putting off writing them up, but in the interest of populating this blog with&lt;/em&gt; something, &lt;em&gt;below lie some disorganised impressions on the topic. Take seriously at your own caution.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The word “biopsychosocial” comes up a lot in lectures, which is directionally good, but the supposedly equal treatment of these factors seems a bit nominal and epistemologically confused. The unspoken implication of a lot of this teaching is that the psyche is the substrate of neuroanatomy and neurochemistry, which is no doubt defensible, but nonetheless establishes a hierarchy in which the psychosocial component is secondary to the biological.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Migrating from Jekyll to Eleventy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/blog-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/blog-migration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As of September 2024, this blog runs on &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. I’m going to leave this up both because it stands as an appraisal of the merits of SSGs in general, and because it serves as a memento mori for the eternal and inescapable Dukkha of Optimisation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;N.B.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;If the term &amp;lsquo;Static Site Generator&amp;rsquo; is unfamiliar to you, I recommend reading &lt;a href=&#34;https://tom.preston-werner.com/2008/11/17/blogging-like-a-hacker.html&#34;&gt;this blogpost&lt;/a&gt; as a primer. Blog like a hacker!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Though it may look the same, the backend of this blog has been drastically simplified. Previously, I was using the static site generator &lt;a href=&#34;https://jekyllrb.com/&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; to build this site, but I have now migrated to a newer, flashier, and much easier to use SSG called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.11ty.dev/&#34;&gt;Eleventy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hello world</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And we are live! First post on this blog. Hopefully first of many.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
